story time story time story time story time story time story time story time story time
i've got another neurodivergent story time for you i've got another neurodivergent so all my
neuro spices this one's for you we got another one for you
mm-hmm uh before i even start i want to let y'all know that smart funny and black t-shirts
and sweatshirts are back they haven't been available for two years so you can actually
get them they're back i found a solution for tees so um lucky you so i don't know about anybody else
but when i was young um i used to be told i sounded white and i always took that to just mean
that i was um kind of like not black enough like that's what i was that's how it was framed like i
wasn't black enough and i didn't like represent my blackness loud enough and um i really
only understood that that was my autism until a year ago so i have a poem so okay so i'm
reading this book right now invisible differences a story of autism adulting and living life in full
color by mademoiselle uh caroline and julie datchez okay and there's a sentence in here that made me say
story time when she talks marguerite wait i'm gonna say it right when she talks marguerite
sounds like a book a 19th century book in complete articulate sentences with faultless grammar
and no slang i have a poem called oreo that i wrote when i was 19 about growing up
and constantly being bullied about this when i was in middle school i was told like every day
at least that's how i remember it like every day i'm gonna beat you up because you talk white
i'm gonna beat you up because you think you white i'm gonna beat you up because you talk like you
smarter than me and this used to drive me nuts because i i never thought that it was just that's how i talk
and so i have a poem called oreo that talks about this i used to be told i sounded white
because i was easily understood my speech didn't hold the rhythm of the hood
an oreo with black on the outside and white in the middle the kids said i didn't sound like my race
not even a little so i but but i wasn't even a perpetrator because that's just what i was
a black girl with white talk who didn't ride the bus so the kids told me i thought i was rich
they said i thought i was all that i got threatened many times to get bashed and whacked even once to be
thrown through a window by ryanika logan so i had to let them know yo i'm not white i don't think
i'm all that my soul is not white on the inside just like yours it's black but until i could quote
tupac and shake it fast until i could use i in my everyday speech and wasn't afraid to skip class
my speech was foreign to my african-american peers ears until i could hold the rhythm of the streets
in my hips and tongue my presence of off blackness was met with blank sayers that onto me they flung
it stung because only till i met the standard set by my rmb loving peers
did i gain entrance into the hip-hop nation i've been living here comfortably as a resident
since the 11th grade of a person with skin of a darker shade than peach
it's funny for a time i thought there was a pinnacle of blackness i had to reach
just to fill out my skin's melanin now i realize it's not that i wasn't black till i was approved of
by my peers they couldn't pass me the baton i've been in this race for 44 years
the experience of being aware of my autism has unlocked a lifetime of mysteries
and the masking that you do you know i had to basically lean into ways of speech
in order to present as more acceptable like my natural way of talking is this
um now once i found hip-hop as like an art form it was natural that my speech changed because
i found a whole voice in hip-hop and music is a very big part of my autism so it's no surprise but as a
youth as i like a youth in orlando florida talking like this was seen as literally insulting
like literally me just talking was insulting you're about to watch what interview and i just again
wanted to shout out all of us who grew up not knowing this about ourselves and just trying oh
she posted it okay and just trying to navigate our way through what's already a very difficult time
because baby adolescence whoo you know what's wild adolescence is a doozy whether you got boobies or not
like that that that's the other part of it it was like if you got if you're flat-chested you're getting
heat if you got boobs you're getting heat either way you're just you're just taking l's you're just
taking l's but um but i do feel like these are the types of things that they don't tell you
they don't tell you that um you know this is a symptom you don't know that i always just thought
it was because my mother was from the caribbean mind you my mother has a whole accent my mother
don't talk like i talk my mother talk like this so shout out to all my neurodivergent
misdiagnosed oreos we were struggling we were struggling
and when i read this line from this book invisible differences where it says when she talks
marguerite sounds like a book and marguerite is the character she's autistic
and it says that she's talks in complete articulate sentences with faultless grammar and no slang
the no slang was like ding ding ding ding because as i said in the poem i had to consciously
decide to say y'all and aight i had to literally insert that into my vernacular to fit in um
and i also think you know not only did i love hip-hop musically however i think because i became hyper
focused on hip-hop i mean i am a hip-hop connoisseur like i mean i'm really a hip-hop head i think it was
also because it the lyricism of hip-hop allowed me an ability to be like verbose and rapid in speech
without being looked at as funny style or as interrogatory and it was so creative in the
lyricism and the rhythm so um yeah like i was i was called like a you think you know everybody and
you know what's funny is that even as an adult i mean when i would see commentary that people would
put on shade room etc a lot of it would be like oh you think um you think she thinks she knows
everything she's so serious she's always talking so serious like she she always talks like she's
somebody teacher it's like yes yes because that is part of my neurodivergence so yes y'all
enjoy your your differences and um lean into them and be um i encourage you to to like be accepting
and graceful with and also like proud of the fact that you managed to mask in a time where you were
already having to deal with just existing you then on top of that manage to figure a way in to
like not always feel left out because that right there is a doozy
we go forth remember smart funny and black tees and smart funny and black sweatshirts
are now available at amandalandexports.com support a real one good night